A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, National Affairs, Office Files of Thomas Cooney FA653
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Communities and Neighborhoods, 1969-1982; V
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC) -- Information Papers and Community and Neighborhood Surveys -- North Ward Educational and Cultural Center, Inc. (Box 10)
  - "The Philadelphia Prototype: An Evaluation of Reverend Leon Sullivan's Economic Development Enterprises", Dec 1969 (Box 10)
  - PRI/CDCs, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Reports -- David A. Smith, 1973 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx -- Work File -- Incl. Site Visit Report to Board of Trustees, Survey of South Bronx Organizations, Related South Bronx Memoranda and Materials, 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- Bronx Venture Corporation, 1979 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- List of South Bronx Organizations and Information (Proposals, Drafts, etc.), 1978 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- Morris Heights Neighborhood Improvement Association, 1977 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- People's Development Corporation, 1979 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- Shepherd's Restoration Corporation, 1979 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- South Bronx Community Housing Corporation, 1979 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- South Bronx Overall Economic Development Corporation, 1979 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- SEBCO Development, Inc., 1979 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- Survival Research and Development Corporation, 1979 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- Tremont Community Council, 1979 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- South Bronx Organization List for C&N Survey, 1979 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- Anita Miller's Memoranda Re: South Bronx, 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- "A Rationale for Investment in the South Bronx" (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Information and Reports Surveys -- General, 1978 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Development Office -- Background Information and Rationale, [1979] (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Development Office, 1979 (Box 10)
  - South Bronx Development Office -- General, 1979 (Box 10)
  - Survey of South Bronx Organizations, Mar 1979 (Box 10)
  - Wilbur Mills/Little Rock, 1969 (Box 10)
- Ford Foundation Administrative/Organizational Files and Additional National Affairs Program Files, 1964-1982; VI
  - Agent Orange Victims International (work file), 1980 (Box 11)
  - Black/White Data and Affirmative Action, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Blacks and Jews -- Voting Trends, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Black and White -- Definitions of, Quotes About (from literature, dictionary), etc. (Box 11)
  - "Black Enterprise" -- April 1979 Issue, Page 19, Franklin Thomas Article, Apr 1979 (Box 11)
  - Blackshear, Warren D. (activities other than Travel and Study Award), 1974-1975 (Box 11)
  - Caribbean Migration -- Memoranda and Correspondence Re: Mexican, Caribbean and Latin American Migration, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Caribbean Migration -- Drafts: Caribbean and Latin American Migration Program Design Paper, Jul 1979 (Box 11)
  - Caribbean Migration -- One-Stop Immigration Centers, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Caribbean Migration -- "Mexican and Caribbean Migration to the United States: A Report to the Ford Foundation" by Wayne A. Cornelius (folder 1), Apr 1979 (Box 11)
  - Caribbean Migration -- "Mexican and Caribbean Migration to the United States: A Report to the Ford Foundation" by Wayne A. Cornelius (folder 2), Apr 1979 (Box 11)
  - Caribbean Migration -- "Mexican and Caribbean Migration to the United States: A Report to the Ford Foundation" by Wayne A. Cornelius (folder 3), Apr 1979 (Box 11)
  - Caribbean Review File Re: Ford Foundation Work in Caribbean and With Caribbean Issues (folder 1), 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Caribbean Review File Re: Ford Foundation Work in Caribbean and With Caribbean Issues (folder 2), 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Caribbean Review File Re: Ford Foundation Work in Caribbean and With Caribbean Issues (folder 3), 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Cascadian Regional Library -- Proposal Re: National Networking, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Chicago Journalism Review, 1969-1974 (Box 11)
  - "Civil Disorders" -- Papers (non-Ford Foundation) and Memorandum to John Coleman, "The Cost of Riots to Negros", 1967 (Box 11)
  - Coleman Memoranda to Committee, 1966 (Box 11)
  - Columbia University School of Journalism -- Summer Journalism Program -- Grant Requests, Notification Letters, RGAs, Memoranda (folder 1), 1969-1976 (Box 11)
  - Columbia University School of Journalism -- Summer Journalism Program -- Grant Requests, Notification Letters, RGAs, Memoranda (folder 2), 1969-1976 (Box 11)
  - Columbia University Journalism Fiscal Year 1973 (working file) (Box 11)
  - Columbia University Summer Journalism (Michele Clark Fellowship) Fiscal Year 1974-1975 -- Columbia Deficit (Box 11)
  - Columbia University Summer Journalism (Michele Clark Fellowship) Fiscal Year 1974-1975 -- February 24 Meeting, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Columbia University Summer Journalism (Michele Clark Fellowship) Fiscal Year 1974-1975 -- General, 1974-1976 (Box 11)
  - Community Educational Exchange Program (CEEP), 1975 (Box 11)
  - Community News Service (working file), 1972-1977 (Box 12)
  - Community News Service Dissolution, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Computer and Computer Meeting Materials, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Conflict Resolutions -- Papers -- Fuchs, Glazer, Isaacs Re: Achieving Minorities and Related Memoranda, 1976-1977 (Box 12)
  - Conflict Resolutions -- Papers by Donald L. Horowitz Re: Ethnic Conflict and Achieving Minorities, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
  - Conflict Resolutions -- Papers -- Citizen, Neighborhood, Criminal incl. Forest Hills Housing Dispute, 1978 (Box 12)
  - Conflict Resolutions -- Correspondence on Conflict Resolutions and Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Conflict Resolutions -- "Ford Foundation: Look at Conflict Resolution" by Sandy Jaffee, Feb 1980 (Box 12)
  - Conflict Resolutions -- RGAs: Conflict Resolutions (CBP, IMCR, CJP), 1978-1980 (Box 12)
  - Conflict Resolutions -- The Snoqualmie River Conflict, Feb 1978 (Box 12)
  - Conflict Resolutions -- "Conflict Resolution: Prospects for the Future" Information Paper, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Congress of Racial Equality (CORE)-Cleveland Foundation History, 1967 (Box 12)
  - Consultant -- Willis, Clayton -- Correspondence Re: Grant Funding Possibilities, 1968-1969 (Box 12)
  - Consultants/Research Contacts -- Adolphus R. Thomas Associates, 1972-1975 (Box 12)
  - Consultants/Research Contacts -- Chambers, Brad (working file), 1973 (Box 12)
  - Consultants/Research Contacts -- Hawkins, Michael, 1973-1975 (Box 12)
  - Consultants/Research Contacts -- Joseph A. Davis Consultants, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Consultants/Research Contacts -- O'Neil, Lawrence H. -- Riverside Research Institute, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Consultants/Research Contacts -- Spivack, Robert -- "Living Journalism", [1970] (Box 12)
  - Consultants/Research Contacts -- Stamper, Evert L., 1969 (Box 12)
  - Consultants/Research Contacts -- Vance, William D. (Adolphus Thomas), 1980 (Box 12)
  - Consultants/Research Contacts -- Waknin, Ben, 1974-1976 (Box 12)
  - Corporation for Public-Private Ventures (CPPV), 1978 (Box 12)
  - Crime -- Ghetto, 1967 (Box 12)
  - Criminal Justice -- Caplan, Gerald Correspondence, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Criminal Justice -- Caplan, Gerald Correspondence -- "Stop Crime" (Anderson), 1977 (Box 12)
  - Ecumenical Institute (working file), 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - Energy -- "Saving Energy: An Idea for a Private-Sector Initiative" Report, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Energy -- Portland-Proposed Energy Policy USHUD -- "Energy Conservation in Portland" Report (Box 13)
  - Energy -- Portland-Proposed Energy Policy USHUD -- Portland Energy Conservation Project, 1977-1978 (Box 13)
  - Federal Programs -- Eligibility, 1977, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Ford Foundation Information Papers, 1968 (Box 13)
  - "Ford Foundation Assistance to Native Americans" -- Ford Foundation Published Booklet, Dec 1977 (Box 13)
  - Ford Foundation Job Descriptions -- Memorandum Re: Preparation of Position Descriptions, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Ford Foundation News -- Incl. Ford Foundation "Letter" and Ford Foundation Published Pamphlets Re: Trustees' Responsibilities and Ford Foundation Publications and Films, 1979-1981 (Box 13)
  - Ford Foundation News Release -- Re: New Ford Foundation Organizational Framework, Apr 6, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Ford Foundation President McGeorge Bundy Statement to House Committee Re: Treasury Department Report on Private Foundations, Feb 20, 1969 (Box 13)
  - Foundation History -- Foundation vs. Congress, 1969 (Box 13)
  - Frederick Douglass Fellowship -- Training Black Reporters (Adams-Afro-American Papers), 1969 (Box 13)
  - Frederick Douglass Fellowship, 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Frederick Douglass Program -- Fellowship/Reports, Summaries (memos, etc.), 1969-1973 (Box 13)
  - Frederick Douglass Program -- Virginia Council on Human Relations, 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - Government -- "One Nation So Many Governments: The Ford Foundation and the Goals of Reform" by Michael Danielson, Alan Hershey, and John Bayne, Jun 1973 (Box 13)
  - Grants -- Memoranda on Various Grants (internal and external), 1970-1977 (Box 13)
  - Grants 1972 (working files) (Box 13)
  - Grant-Making -- Cuninggim Report to Ford Foundation President Re: Reaching Decisions on Grants, Nov 19, 1973 (Box 13)
  - Grant Information (General) -- Correspondence (TEC), 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - Grantee Information -- Brooklyn Educational and Cultural Alliance, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Grantee Information -- National Association of Private Industry Council, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Grantee Information -- New England Municipal Center, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Grantee Information -- New York City Mission Society Re: Alcoholics Anonymous, 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - Grantee Information -- The Nova Institute Re: Study of Community Boards in City Government, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Grantee Information -- South Carolina Committee for the Humanities, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Grantee Information -- The Greater Hartford Process, Inc., 1979 (Box 14)
  - Grantee Information -- United Way of America Re: Conference Support, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Grantee Information -- Fiscal Status Report (2/16/1980-5/16/1980) (Box 14)
  - Grants (Health, Behavior, Nutrition related) -- Better Boys Foundation, 1974-1977 (Box 14)
  - Grants (Health, Behavior, Nutrition related) -- Commonweal -- Michael Lerner, 1974-1977 (Box 14)
  - Grants (Health, Behavior, Nutrition related) -- Lewis, Dr. Dorothy, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Grants (Health, Behavior, Nutrition related) -- Meharry Medical -- J. Carter, 1975 (Box 14)
  - Grants (Health, Behavior, Nutrition related) -- MIT -- Wurtman, 1976-1977 (Box 14)
  - Grants (Health, Behavior, Nutrition related) -- University of California, Berkeley -- Margen and Lerner, 1976-1978 (Box 14)
  - Grants (Health, Behavior, Nutrition related) -- University of Minnesota -- Deinard, 1976-1979 (Box 14)
  - Handicapped (working file), 1980 (Box 14)
  - Humanities and the Arts -- Grant Recommendations Re: Theater and Playwright Work, 1964-1977 (Box 14)
  - Interlochen (working file), 1975 (Box 14)
  - Interlochen -- Donald Barr Report on Interlochen (magnetic reel), 1975 (Box 14)
  - John Jay College -- John Pfeiffer, 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Juvenile Violence Meeting (folder 1), Sep 20-21, 1976 (Box 14)
  - Juvenile Violence Meeting (folder 2), Sep 20-21, 1976 (Box 14)
  - Juvenile Delinquent Biology/Reports, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Juvenile Delinquency Reports, 1976 (Box 14)
  - Juvenile Delinquency -- Judge Driscoll -- Proposal, 1977 (Box 14)
  - Kennedy Travel and Study Awards -- Appendices I-VIII, 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Kennedy Travel and Study Awards, [1970] (Box 14)
  - Kennedy Travel and Study Awards -- Bruno, Jerry, 1968-1972 (Box 15)
  - Kennedy Travel and Study Awards -- Walinsky, Adam, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Kennedy Travel and Study Awards -- Mills Hearings (2/1969), 1968-1969 (Box 15)
  - Kennedy Travel and Study Awards -- FAP, 1968 (Box 15)
  - Kennedy Travel and Study Awards -- Letters, 1969 (Box 15)
  - "Law School Teaching of Legislation" -- Report by Joseph Dolan, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration (LEAA) (folder 1), 1978 (Box 15)
  - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration (LEAA) (folder 2), 1978 (Box 15)
  - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration (LEAA), 1979 (Box 15)
  - Learning, Seminar on (E. Meade), 1977 (Box 15)
  - Mass Media -- Southern Courier -- Third Grant Request (Michael Lottman), 1968-1969 (Box 15)
  - Media -- Materials Relating to Broadcasting, Communications Inside and Outside the Foundation, 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - Metropolitan Applied Research Center, Inc. (MARC) (working file), 1970-1971 (Box 15)
  - Metropolitan Applied Research Center, Inc. (MARC) (working file), 1972-1973 (Box 15)
  - Metropolitan Applied Research Center, Inc. (MARC) (working file), 1974-1975 (Box 15)
  - Miami Riot -- Reviews, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Michigan Fund, 1977-1980 (Box 16)
  - Minority Contractors Assistance Project, Inc. (MCAP) Report -- Final Reports and Studies, 1977-1979 (Box 16)
  - Minority Grants -- Analysis of Fiscal Year 1972 Grants -- Amounts to Various Minorities/Mott Foundation (John Bayne), 1973 (Box 16)
  - Monitoring, 1972-1975 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous Papers -- LEAA, 1978 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous Papers -- Responses to "Meeting" Letter Re: Future Health, Nutrition, Behavior Meetings, 1978 (Box 16)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) (working file), 1972-1973 (Box 16)
  - NAACP (working file) (incl. cassette tape), 1974-1979 (Box 16)
  - NAACP Grants -- Grant Requests, Action Forms, Notification Letters, 1967-1979 (Box 16)
  - NAACP Special Contribution Fund, Inc. (68-469), 1972-1981 (Box 16)
  - NAACP -- Mississippi, 1976 (Box 16)
  - NAACP -- Travel (working file), 1973 (Box 16)
  - National Affairs -- Old Program Priorities, 1969-1972 (Box 16)
  - National Affairs -- Assessment of Grants -- Update of 6/70 Docket, Jun 6, 1973 (Box 17)
  - National Affairs -- Breakdown of National Affairs Grants, 1974-1975 (Box 17)
  - National Affairs -- Status Report, Nov 1976 (Box 17)
  - National Affairs -- Program Action History Index, 1980 (Box 17)
  - National Affairs -- Annual Report, 1980 (Box 17)
  - National Affairs -- Current Interests, 1980 (Box 17)
  - National Affairs -- DAP -- Mergers and Close Outs for National Affairs Grants, May 1980 (Box 17)
  - National Affairs -- Planning Reports, Fiscal Year 1980, 1979-1981 (Box 17)
  - National Commission on Employment and Unemployment Statistics (NCEUS) -- Memos, 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - National Conference of Catholic Charities (working file), 1978 (Box 17)
  - NORC "Crisis", 1967 (Box 17)
  - Papers for Board of Trustees Re: Program Planning (Bundy papers), Dec 1976 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Evaluation -- Report, 1976 (Box 17)
  - Preliminary Program Planning -- Budget 2/1981 for National Affairs Program (Box 17)
  - Preliminary Program Planning -- Incl. Discussion of New Program Themes, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Preparatory School Proposal for Minority Students, 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - Presidency Task Force, 1970 (Box 17)
  - Project Evaluations, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Public Policy -- Task Force on Contemporary Society in Humanistic Perspective -- Meeting Materials, Proposals, Report, 1979-1980 (Box 17)
  - Publications Assistance -- Financial Support for Publishing Ventures (working file), 1975 (Box 17)
  - Publishing -- Ford Foundation Program Proposal, May 1979 (Box 17)
  - Race and Ethnicity -- "The Educational and Other Development of the Negro" and Grant Request Re: Educational and Professional Opportunities for Black Students/Professionals, Sep 1965-Nov 1966 (Box 17)
  - Race and Ethnicity -- "The White Problem" Draft Paper by S.M. Miller, Feb 26, 1969 (Box 17)
  - Race and Ethnicity -- Discussion Paper Re: Basic Research Needs (Teper), 1974 (Box 17)
  - Race and Ethnicity -- Task Force Report and Job Satisfaction Report -- B. Whiting, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Race Relations Information Center, 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Race Relations Information Center (Survey of File Use), 1970 (Box 17)
  - Racial Policy Issues, 1976-1977 (Box 17)
  - Recommendation for Grant Action (RGAs) -- Proposition 13 RGA, 1978 (Box 17)
  - Rejection Letters -- Ford Foundation Protocols for Composition (Helen Dickerson files), 1973 (Box 17)
  - Retirement/Termination Papers for Thomas Cooney, 1977-1978 (Box 17)
  - Science in the Ford Foundation (Marshall Robinson et al.), 1977 (Box 17)
  - Social Development -- Program Status Report and Grants Summaries, 1968-1969 (Box 17)
  - Social Development -- Bibliographies/Inclusion in 1977 Annual Report (Box 17)
  - Social Development Program History -- Memoranda to John Coleman Re: Grants and Ford Foundation Work Concerning Minority Groups, Program Possiblities for Under-Represented Groups; Meeting Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - Social Development Program History -- Report, "Grants and Projects Related to the Development of the American Negro;" McGeorge Bundy Address Re: Equal Opportunity; Memo Re: Tactics of Philanthropy; Budget Materials; Commitment to Interest of Minorites, etc., 1966-1973 (Box 17)
  - Social Leverage -- Paper, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Southeast Community Organization (SECO)/SDI Site Visit -- Background and Notes, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Schultz, Chiz -- Tapes, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Schultz, Chiz -- Chiz Schultz, Inc., 1974 (Box 18)
  - Speeches (Ford Foundation staff), 1976 (Box 18)
  - Staff Workload Reports, [1968] (Box 18)
  - Study and Notes Re: Ford Foundation Operating Activities incl. Mail Service, Travel Expenses, Grant Funding, etc., 1969 (Box 18)
  - Study and Notes Re: Staff Workload Survey and Grant Activities, 1969 (Box 18)
  - Summary Memoranda, Reports, Speeches by/to Mitchell Sviridoff -- "Go Betweens for Social Change" by Mitchell Sviridoff, Mar 1978 (Box 18)
  - Summary Memoranda, Reports, Speeches by/to Mitchell Sviridoff -- Sviridoff Speech (draft) Re: Conflict Resolution (Box 18)
  - Summary Memoranda, Reports, Speeches by/to Mitchell Sviridoff -- Memoranda to Sviridoff Re: LISC, 1980 (Box 18)
  - System within System -- "The Improvement of the System within the System" Report by William Lee Miller, 1976 (Box 18)
  - System within System -- Report, Abridged and Non-Abridged Versions by William Lee Miller, 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Teen Pregnancy -- Visit to Texas Programs for Teen Parents, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Transfer of Economic Power Re: Economic Development, 1970 (Box 18)
  - Travel and Study -- Cole, Ernest, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Travel and Study -- Jenkins, Adelbert H., 1976 (Box 18)
  - Travel and Study -- Kelly, John Ellison, 1974 (Box 18)
  - Travel and Study -- MacLeod, Gordon, 1973 (Box 18)
  - Travel and Study -- Memoranda Pertaining to Travel and Study Awards, 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - TVA and Social Development -- Ray Marshall, [1972] (Box 18)
  - United Church of Christ -- Background Information, 1967 (Box 18)
  - United Church of Christ, 1968-1971 (Box 18)
  - United Church of Christ (working file), 1971-1973 (Box 18)
  - United Church of Christ -- Discrimination in Broadcasting Grant Report, 1980 (Box 18)
  - United Press International, 1971-1973 (Box 19)
  - Urban Poverty and the Disadvantaged/Child Development under Conditions of Urban Poverty -- Reports, 1981 (Box 19)
  - VERA Institute of Justice -- General Correspondence (working file), 1976-1977 (Box 19)
  - Vera Report, "Violent Delinquents" -- 2nd Final Draft, Apr 1977 (Box 19)
  - "Violent Delinquents - A Report and Recommendations to the Ford Foundation" (folder 1), Apr 1977 (Box 19)
  - "Violent Delinquents - A Report and Recommendations to the Ford Foundation" (folder 2), Apr 1977 (Box 19)
  - Violence Report (Strasburg), 1976-1978 (Box 19)
  - "White Attitudes" -- Ford Foundation Campaign, 1968 (Box 19)
  - White Underclass, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Youth and Delinquency -- "An Introductory Overview of Youth Programs in New York City" by Starry Krueger and Related Memorandum, Mar 1975 (Box 19)
  - Youth and Delinquency, 1976 (Box 19)
- Non-Ford Foundation Related Papers, 1961-1979; VII
  - Bookfind Book Reviews -- Thomas Cooney's Reviews and Writings, 1956-1960 (Box 19)
  - Borgmann, Carl W. and Thomas Cooney, "The Conservation of Matter", 1969-1972 (Box 19)
  - Dalton School, 1974 (Box 19)
  - Ideas in Transit -- Thomas Cooney's Personal and Professional Writings and Reflections, 1961-1966 (Box 19)
  - Leo Cooney Documents -- Cooney Genealogy incl. Photographs (copies of c. 1894 photos) and Photocopies of Civil War Company Muster Rolls and Casualty Form (1860s), 1968 (Box 19)
  - Personal Correspondence (non-Ford), 1979 (Box 19)
- Appendix A: Reports, 1973-1980
  - Becker, Jane; Evaluation and Research on U.S. Government -- Domestic Nutrition Intervention Programs, Nov 1974 (Report #019874)
  - Danielson, Michael N., Alan M. Hershey, and John M. Bayne; One Nation, So Many Governments -- Goals of Reform, Jun 1973 (Report #019889)
  - Dolan, Joseph; Law School Teaching of Legislation -- A Report to the Ford Foundation (Report #019884)
  - Ellis, James R.; National Affairs Program -- Status Report, Nov 1976 (Report #019885)
  - Ford Foundation; Community Development Corporations -- New Instruments to Overcome Poverty, 1972 (Report #019878)
  - Jaffee, Sandy; Ford Foundation -- Look at Conflict Resolution, Feb 29, 1980 (Report #019881)
  - Lerner, Michael and Cynthia Johnston; Tomorrow's Children -- The Role of Nutritional and Environmental Stressors in the Learning and Behavior..., 1979 (Report #019870)
  - Miller, William Lee; the Improvement of the System Within the System -- Notes on Ethos of American Liberal Reform, 1976 (Report #019887)
  - Schultz, S.R. and S. Margen; Study of Medical-Health Evaluations Performed on Juveniles in Placement, Nov 1979 (Report #019875)
  - Schwartz, David C.; Influence of Health on Adolescent's Social Adjustment amd Educational Achievement in a Residential..., n.d. (Report #019871)
  - Sharpe, Richard S.; Report of the PPSO Humanistic Perspectives on Contemporary Society Task Force, Oct 10, 1980 (Report #019882)
  - Simmons, Ozzie G.; Health, Nutrition, Population Activities in Thailand, Apr 1, 1980 (Report #019877)
  - Stainsby, Charles; Public, Private Enterprise in Britain and America (Report #019873, Report #019872)
  - Sviridoff, Mitchell; Go-Betweens for Social Change, Mar 6, 1978 (Report #019886)
  - Teper, Shirley; Discussion -- Basic Research Needs in Race and Ethnicity, Jan 25, 1974 (Report #019888)
  - Weingarten, Victor; Report to the Ford Foundation -- Federal Programs in Nutrition (Report #019876)
  - Conflict Resolution -- Prospects for the Future -- Information Paper, n.d. (Report #019883)
  - The Local Initiatives Support Corporation -- Community and Neighborhood Revitialization, Jun 1, 1980 (Report #019879)
  - The Local Initiatives Support Corporation -- National Support for Local Development, Mar 25, 1980 (Report #019880)